[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：然后是JavaScript，所以概括地说，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And then there was JavaScript, so to recap,
首先是大爆炸。
first, there was The Big Bang.
然后是“人类的沉沦”，然后是JavaScript。
Then there was The Down of Man and then there was JavaScript.
所以我是第一个认识到JavaScript有好的部分的人，
So I was the first person to recognize that JavaScript had good parts,
这是21世纪的第一个重要发现。
that was the first important discovery of the 21st century.
当我宣布我的结果时，他们遭到了疯狂的怀疑。
And when I announced my results they were met with wild skepticism.
没有办法，JavaScript中不可能有任何好的部分。
No way, there cannot possibly be any good parts in JavaScript.
但事实证明，我的结果得到了验证
But it turns out that my results were validated and in
事实上JavaScript有一些非常好的部分。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：这是最重要的
fact JavaScript has some very good parts. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: This is the most important
21世纪的发现。
discovery of the 21st Century.
这是你做的吗？&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：是的，我做了。
And you made this? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, I did that.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[听不见]
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [INAUDIBLE]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以我会给予
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So I'll give
你有一些历史背景。
you some historical background.
在加州大学国家超级计算应用中心
At the National Center for Supercomputing Applications at the University of
伊利诺伊州，Urbana-Champaign，有一群孩子正在发展
Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, there are a bunch of kids who are developing
用于Internet的客户端程序。
a client program for the Internet.
当时，有许多正在考虑的协议
At that time, there were a number of protocols that were being considered for
互联网向人们传递信息的方式。
the way that the Internet was going to deliver information to people.
有WAIS，Archie，Gopher
There was WAIS, Archie, Gopher,
FTP，Finger和其他一些和万维网。
FTP, Finger and a few others and the World Wide Web.
这些人不知道谁会赢。
And these guys didn't know which of those was going to win.
所以他们写了一个为他们所有人工作的程序
So they wrote a program that worked for all of them and
他们称这个程序为马赛克。
they called the program mosaic.
而且因为他们实现查看器的方式
And because of the way that they implemented the viewer for
万维网。
the World Wide Web.
万维网，他们做的事情是他们想出了
The World Wide Web one and the thing that they did was they came up with
一种叫做图像标签的东西允许。
something called the image tag which allowed.
显示图像的网络，
The web to display images,
这是其他格式不容易做到的事情。
which is something that the other formats couldn't easily do.
而且因为Web可以显示图像，所以它看起来就像你想要的那样
And because the web could display images, it could look like what you wanted it to
即使它不是你想要的那样，这是有效率的
be even if it wasn't what you wanted it to be, and that was efficient and
这让万维网赢了，一切都从那里起飞了。
that allowed the web to win and everything took off from there.
一群来自那个项目的人，就是在那里被引诱到加州的，
A bunch of the people from that project where it lured to California,
在那里他们成为了一家名为Netscape的公司的一部分。
where they became part of a company called Netscape.
Netscape制造了第一个名为Netscape Navigator的商业网络浏览器，
Netscape made the first commercial web browser called Netscape Navigator,
这是一个巨大的打击。
and it was a huge hit.
它有点打乱了一切，然后他们正在计划做什么
It kinda disrupted everything, and they were then planning what to do for
导航员2。
Navigator 2.
他们还增加了一系列新功能，包括对电子商务的支持。
And they added a bunch of new features including support for electronic commerce.
他们还想让最终用户编程变得容易。
They also wanted to make it easy for end user programming.
他们记得在Macintosh上有一种叫做HyperCard的东西。
They remembered something that had been on the Macintosh called HyperCard.
HyperCard是一个简单的应用程序创建程序，基于
HyperCard was a simple application creation program based
关于一堆卡片的简单比喻，这是一种事件驱动的脚本。
on a simple metaphor of stacks of cards and it was an event driven script thing.
而且它非常容易使用和
And it was remarkably easy to use and
他们希望在网络浏览器中有类似的东西。
they wanted something like that in the web browser.
所以他们把这份工作给了这个人。
So they gave that job to this guy.
这是Brendan Eich非常聪明的家伙，他曾经是Silicon Graphics的内核黑客，
This is Brendan Eich very smart guy, he'd been a kernel hacker at Silicon Graphics,
他的想法是，他将编写一个Scheme解释器来完成这项工作。
his idea was he would write a Scheme interpreter to do this.
他被告知不要做计划，做一种人们喜欢的语言。
And he was told no don't do Scheme, do a language that people like.
让它看起来像Joller，Visual Basic，一些流行的东西。
Make it look like Joller, Visual Basic, something popular.
这是给孩子们的。
This is for the kids.
所以他有十天的时间来创造这个新的原型
So he was given ten days to create a prototype of this new
交互式浏览器和在这十天里。
interactive browser and in those ten days.
他设计并
He designed and
实现了一种新的编程语言，这是一个惊人的成就。
implemented a new programming language which is an amazing achievement.
所以他从Java学习了语法。
So from Java he took syntax.
事实上，JavaScript的大部分错误都是以前
In fact, most of the things that are wrong with JavaScript are things that were
继承自Java。
inherited from Java.
有一种叫做Scheme的语言，它是Lisp的一种方言
There's a language called Scheme which is a dialect of Lisp that was
麻省理工学院开发的。
developed at MIT.
Scheme有lambdas，Scheme就是这么叫它的函数的
And Scheme has lambdas, that's what Scheme calls its functions and
他采用了Scheme函数，并将它们放入了他的语言中。
he took Scheme functions and he put them into his language.
还有一种叫Self的Smalltalk方言是最早在
And there's a dialect of Smalltalk called Self that was developed first at
施乐Parc，后来在Sun实验室。
Xerox Parc and then later at Sun Labs.
Self，采用了Smalltalk，这是第一种现代古典语言，
Self, took Smalltalk, which was the first modern classical language,
面向对象的语言，并使其更好。
object oriented language and made it better.
更好的性能和
Both better performance and
通过从Smalltalk中删除一个功能来使用更具表现力的用户。
more expressive user to use by removing one feature from Smalltalk.
人们通过从另一种语言中删除东西来创造一种新语言的情况并不常见
It's uncommon where someone makes a new language by removing things from another
语言。
language.
通常是增加更多的东西。
Usually it's adding more stuff.
他们从Smalltalk中删除的是课程。
The thing they removed from Smalltalk was classes.
通过删除类，他们可以使其更快，并且
By removing classes, they could make it faster, and
他们可以让编程变得更好。
they could make it much better to program.
所以，他拿出了想法，并把它放进了他的语言中
And so, he took out idea and put it into his language and
那个斗篷叫它LiveScript
that Cape called it LiveScript.
现在，当这种情况发生时，另一种语言正在
Now, while that was going on there was another language that was being
由Sun公司的一个叫James Gosling的家伙开发的。
developed by a guy at Sun named James Gosling.
他从一个叫做“绿色谈话”的东西开始。
He started with something called Green talk.
然后他被调到一家开发机顶盒应用程序的新公司
He was then moved into a new company that was developing set top box applications
他们的语言变成了橡树。
their his language became called oak.
那家公司倒闭了，所以他又回到了Sun和
That company failed so his brought back into Sun and
他们试图弄清楚我们现在用这种语言做什么。
they try to figure out what do we do with this language now.
互联网变得流行，网络变得流行，
The Internet was becoming popular, the web becoming popular,
他们用这种语言编写了一个网络浏览器。
they wrote a web browser in this language.
那个叫做HotJava的浏览器非常成功，至少在
That browser called HotJava was wildly successful at least for
很短的时间和语言。
a short time and the language that.
他们把它写了下来，把它的名字改成了Java，它变得非常成功。
They wrote it in, had its name changed to Java and it became wildly successful.
太多了以至于有些人在制造噪音
So much so that some were making noise that
Java语言将成为软件的未来。
the Java language was going to be the future of software.
如果您将所有程序设计为针对Java虚拟机而不是
That if you design all of your programs to target the Java virtual machine instead of
我们可以从微软手中解放出来的操作系统。
the operating system we can be liberated from Microsoft.
这是一个非常成功的信息，Java就是这样迅速崛起的。
And that was a wildly successful message and Java shoots up like that.
这是历史上最成功的一种新编程语言的推出。
It is the most successful launch of a new programming language in history.
太神奇了。
It's amazing.
在网景(Netscape)，他们也提出了类似的主张。
At Netscape, they're making similar claims.
他们说，如果你把你的应用程序设计成针对网络浏览器。
They're saying if you design your applications to target the web browser.
不管我们使用的是什么操作系统，而且
It doesn't matter what operating system we're on, and
再一次，我们可以从微软手中解放出来。
again, we can be liberated from Microsoft.
现在这两家公司意识到，如果我们都在追逐微软
Now these two companies realized, if we're both going after Microsoft
我们最好一起工作，因为如果我们不合作。
we'd probably better work together because if we don't.
微软让我们互相竞争，我们都会输。
Microsoft play us off against each other and we'll both lose.
所以他们结成了联盟，他们同意的第一件事
So they form an alliance, and the first thing they agree
on是Netscape将Java添加到Web浏览器。
on is that Netscape adds Java to the web browser.
作为交换，Sun将放弃他们的热Java浏览器，
And in exchange for that, Sun will drop their hot java browser,
反正也不是很完整。
which wasn't very complete anyway.
所以Chuck这很容易同意
So Chuck, that's easy to agree to.
第二步
Step number two,
Sun说你必须杀掉LiveScript，因为这是一个尴尬。
Sun says you have to kill LiveScript because that's an embarrassment.
我们看到Java是您永远需要的最后一种编程语言。
We're seeing that Java is the last programming language you'll ever need.
你不能同时引入另一种新的语言
You can't then also be introducing another new language
你只是让我们看看这个。
you're just making us look at that.
那就杀了它。
So kill it.
网景拒绝杀死它有两个原因。
Netscape refused to kill it for two reasons.
一个是他们想要一种适合初学者和Java的语言
One is they wanted a language for beginners and Java and that language you
需要很多关于Java的具体知识才能写Hello world。
need a lot of specific knowledge about Java just to write hello world.
他们想要进入门槛低得多的东西，但是
They wanted something with a much lower barrier to entry but
还有一个实际问题。
there's also a practical problem.
他们想马上推出新的浏览器，所以他们把Java放进去的方式
They wanted to launch the new browser right away and so the way they put Java in
他们让Java通过名为Liveconnect的接口与LiveScript对话。
was they had Java talk to LiveScript through an interface called LiveConnect.
因此LiveScript可以与Java可以与之交谈的浏览器进行对话
So LiveScript could talk to the browser Java can talk to
LiveScript到Liveconnect，如果他们把LiveScript去掉，Java就不能工作了。
LiveScript through LiveConnect and if they took LiveScript out, Java wouldn't work.
因此，为了让Java进入那里，他们必须推迟发布
And so, in order to get Java in there they'd have to delay the launching of
新的浏览器，他们不想这样做，
the new browser and they didn't want to do that,
因为他们上网的时间，他们等不起那么长时间。
because they were on Internet time and they couldn't afford to wait that long.
所以他们的联盟陷入僵局
So their alliance was at an impasse and
当网景的创始人之一可能是
almost failed when one of the founders of Netscape maybe as
一个笑话建议他们将LiveScript的名称改为JavaScript。
a joke suggested that they change the name of LiveScript to JavaScript.
并且他们将其定位为Java的子集而不是一种新的语言，
And that they position it not as a new language but as a subset of Java,
解释的Java，这是愚蠢的，因为Java是解释的Java。
interpreted Java, which was silly because Java was interpreted Java.
是爪哇愚蠢的弟弟。
It was Java's stupid little brother.
所以他们出去开了一个记者招待会，在会上他们撒了谎
So they went out and held a press conference in which they lied about
这两种语言的关系。
the relationship of these two languages.
这个谎言的回声仍然在互联网上回荡得相当响亮。
And echoes of that lie still reverberate pretty loudly through the Internet.
同时，微软注意到这两家公司
Meanwhile, Microsoft has noticed that there are these two companies in
准备摧毁微软的加州。
California that are getting ready to destroy Microsoft.
他们还没准备好
And they weren't ready for that yet.
所以微软完全错过了互联网上的网络。
So Microsoft had completely missed the web in the Internet.
他们认为电信的未来将是传真
They thought the future of telecommunications was going to be fax
还有有线电视。
and cable TV.
所以他们出去了，买了一家浏览器公司。
So they went out, they bought a browser company.
这是另一个从伊利诺伊州分离出来的叫做Spyglass的公司。
It was another spin-off out of Illinois called Spyglass.
拿走了他们的东西，将其重新标记为Internet Explorer，然后
Took their thing, relabeled it as Internet Explorer, and
决定我们也需要这些JavaScript东西之一。
decided we need to get one of these JavaScript things too.
所以他们安排了一个团队对第一个JavaScript引擎进行逆向工程。
So they put a team on reverse engineering the first JavaScript engine.
现在看来十天的时间对于设计来说太短了
Now it turns out ten days is way too short a time to design and
实现一种编程语言，有很多错误，
implement a programming language, and there are lots of errors, lots of bugs,
很多设计缺陷，很多错误。
lots of design defects, lots of blunders.
微软团队发现并仔细记录了所有这些文件，并复制了它们。
The Microsoft team discovers and carefully documents all of them and replicates them.
现在，通常，当微软去敲定什么的时候，
Now usually, when Microsoft goes to knock something off,
他们情不自禁地对它做了自己的事情。
they can't help doing their own thing to it.
例如，当比尔盖茨告诉他们我想要一台Macintosh时，他们创建了Windows，好吗？
For example, when Bill Gates told them I want a Macintosh they built Windows, okay?
他没有要Windows，他要的是Macintosh，那就是
He didn't ask for Windows he asked for Macintosh and that's
但是在这个案子上他们完全正确。
how goes there but on this case they got it exactly right.
事实上，他们能够保持写一次到处运行的承诺，
And in fact, they were able to keep the write once run everywhere promise that
Java未能保持。
Java was failing to keep.
事实上，由于没有做到这一点，
And in fact, having not done that,
我们今天不会讨论这门语言，但稍后会讲到这一点。
we wouldn't be talking about this language today but will get to that later.
所以他们不能称之为JavaScript，因为Sun声称拥有
So but they couldn't call it JavaScript because Sun had claimed ownership of
JavaScript商标。
the JavaScript trademark.
尽管它们与语言的发展毫无关系，因为
Even though they had nothing to do with the development of the language because
他们声称拥有Java这个词。
they claimed to own the word Java.
事实上，他们是在敲诈咖啡公司，让他们敢于拥有这个世界
And in fact, they were shaking down coffee companies to daring to have the world
Java在他们的URL中，这是真的。
java in their URLs, this is true.
因此，他们称之为JScript，就像他们称之为Java J+的实现一样，
So, they call it JScript, just as they call their implementation of Java J++,
因为他们无法获得使用商标的许可。
because they couldn't get a license to use the trademark.
因此，现在Netscape担心微软将拥抱并扩展我们，
So, now Netscape is alarmed that Microsoft is going to embrace and extend us,
所以我们会失去对JavaScript的控制。
so we're gonna lose control of JavaScript.
我们该怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
我们需要制定一个标准，所以他们去了W3C，然后说，W3C，
We need to make a standard, so they went to W3C, and said, W3C,
我们已经为网络开发了一种编程语言。
we have developed a programming language for the web.
我们希望你能帮助我们把它变成一个标准。
We'd like you to help us make it a standard.
现在看来，W3C一直在等待机会告诉Netscape去死吧。
Now turns out W3C had been waiting for a chance to tell Netscape to go to hell.
所以他们让网景见鬼去吧。
So they told Netscape to go to hell.
所以网景后来去了ISO。
So Netscape then went to ISO.
最终，他们最终与欧洲计算机制造商协会(European Computer Manufacducers Association)合作。
Eventually they end up with the European Computer Manufacturers Association.
对于一家加州软件公司来说，这是一条漫长的路要走。
Which is a long way to go for a California software company.
但ECMA同意，是的，我们将帮助您制定标准。
But ECMA agrees, yes we'll help you make a standard.
所以他们召集了一个委员会。
So they convene a committee.
微软加入了委员会，微软主导了委员会。
Microsoft joins the committee, Microsoft dominates the committee.
基本上，该标准是基于微软的Notes
Basically, the standard is based on Microsoft's Notes
这是他们在逆向工程原始JavaScript解释器时所做的。
that they made in reverse engineering the original JavaScript interpreter.
他们坚持认为所有的错误，所有的缺陷
And they insist that all of those bugs, all those blunders, all those defects
保持在它们今天仍然存在的标准中。
remain in the standard where they still exist today.
所以，有很多故意出错的东西永远不会被修复。
So, there's a lot that's intentionally wrong which will never be repaired.
现在，当他们想要发表它是我们所说的标准，
Now, when they want to publish it was what we call the standard,
他们不能称之为JavaScript，因为它是SUN的商标。
they can't call it JavaScript because it's a sun trademark.
所以，他们踢来踢去其他的标题，网页脚本，网络脚本，他们不能同意这样，
So, they kick around other titles, web script, net script, they can't agree so,
这是与工作标题一起出版的。
it's published with the working title.
ECMAScript，这可能是有史以来在编程语言上使用的最糟糕的名称
ECMAScript which is maybe the worst name ever put on a programming language and
今天仍然存在困惑JavaScript之间的区别是什么，
confusion still exists today what's the difference between JavaScript,
J脚本ECMAScript。
J-Script ECMAScript.
有些人认为他们三个非常相似，但是
There are people out there who think that they are three remarkably similar but
现在不同的语言。
different now languages.
不，他们三个愚蠢的名字代表一种愚蠢的语言，所以
No, their three silly names for one silly language, so
JavaScript是一种标准化的语言。
JavaScript is a standardized language.
IE的大多数版本都是第三版
The edition that is in most versions of IE is the Third Edition
1999年12月出版。
which was published in December of 1999.
在那个完成之前，开始了第四版的工作，这个版本持续了
Before that one was finished work began on a fourth edition which went on for
十年后被遗弃了。
ten years and was abandoned.
2009年，出版了第五版，其中定义了两种语言，一种是严格的语言，另一种是
In 2009, a fifth edition was published which defines two languages, a Strict and
默认情况下，今天下午我们将更多地讨论该方言。
Default, we'll talk more about that dialect this afternoon.
最近，第六版出版了，最终将
And then recently, the sixth edition was published and which will eventually
找到它进入浏览器的方式，我们将在第三天讨论更多。
find its way into browsers, we'll talk more about that on the third day.
那么坏的部分是从哪里来的呢？
So where do bad parts come from?
我认为有三个来源。
And I think there are three sources.
一个是遗产，在任何语言中都会发生很多事情
One is legacy, a lot of what happens in any language
就是重复以前语言中发生的错误。
is repeating mistakes that happened in previous languages.
JavaScript中的大部分错误并不是JavaScript独有的，
And most of what is wrong in JavaScript is not unique to JavaScript,
它在很多其他语言中也是错误的。
it's wrong in lots of other languages too.
出于某种原因，它在JavaScript中看起来更愚蠢，
For some reason, it just looks stupider in JavaScript,
我不知道为什么会这样，但很明显是这样。
I don't know why that is the case but it is clearly the case.
另一个是良好的意图，有一些功能被添加到
Another is good intentions, there are a number of features that were added to
语言使它变得更容易，但却没能使它变得更容易。
the language to make it easier which failed to make it easier.
类似分号插入，类型强制，当
Things like with semi-colon insertion, type coercion, when
暗示全局变量都是为了让人们更容易使用语言，但是
imply global variables were all intended to make the language easier for people but
它们实际上让它变得更加困难，至少对于专业程序员来说是这样。
they actually make it much harder at least for professional programmers.
然后匆匆忙忙，十天的时间对于设计和设计来说太短了
And then haste, ten days is just way too short a time to design and
实现编程语言。
implement a programming language.
布兰登并不打算
Brendan did not intend for
他的概念证明将作为产品出货，但网景做到了这一点。
his proof of concept to be shipped as a product but Netscape did that.
我认为这是不可原谅的，他为此受苦。
I think that was inexcusable and he suffered for that.
这是一件不幸的事，所以
It was an unfortunate thing, so for
最主要的部分是给你一个比较。
the most part are give you a comparison.
也许历史上设计得最好的编程语言是Smalltalk 80。
Maybe the best designed programming language in history was Smalltalk 80.
施乐Parc花了十年的时间设计，提炼，
Xerox PARC spent a decade designing, refining,
测试，改进语言。
testing, improving that language.
他们花了几乎和网景一样多的时间
They spent almost as many years as Netscape
花了几天的时间指定语言。
spent days in assigning the language.
我认为施乐的做法是正确的，尽管社区并不同意。
And I think Xerox got it right even though the community did not agree.
因此，在大多数情况下，坏的部分可以避免，这是伟大的。
So for the most part the bad parts can be avoided which is great.
坏部分的问题不是它们没用，而是它们很危险
The problem with the bad parts isn't that they are useless it's they are dangerous